<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="module_3_name">Module 2</string>

    <string name="lesson_3_name">Lesson 1</string>

    <string name="lesson_3_title">Loops</string>

    <string name="loops">You may run into a situation where you need to run the same snippet of
    code several times over. One may think that they could just copy and paste those few snippets
    however many times needed. The problem is this is really inefficient and would take a long
    time. Luckily, there is a way to accomplish this with only a few lines of code. We can use "loops"
    to iterate through a specific line of code however many times we want, or until a certain
    condition is met. In Python, we use two different types of loops: While loops and For loops</string>

    <string name="while_loops">A while loops can be used to loop through code until a certain condition is met.
    They are commonly used with boolean variables, for example the loop keeps going until the variable is assigned
    a value of either true or false. However, they can be used for pretty much any condition. If I wanted to keep
    adding 1 to an int variable until that variable\'s value was 10, my while loop might look something like this:
    </string>

    <string name="for_loops">We can use for loops to iterate through a sequence or list of items. For example
    if we have an array that\'s defined as:\n
        languages = ["python", "Java", "Kotlin"]\n
    and we wanted to print out each item in the list, we would use the loop like so:</string>

    <string name="char_loop">You can also use a for loop through each letter in a string. In this case
    the string acts as a char array. It would look like this:</string>


    <string-array name="module_3_questions">
        <!--All of the questions and answer choices are stored into one string-array.-->
        <item >Which loop iterates until a condition is met?</item> <!-- Question 1-->
        <item >For</item> <!-- Answer choice 1-->
        <item>Foreach</item> <!-- Answer choice 2-->
        <item>While</item> <!-- Answer choice 3-->
        <item>Switch</item> <!-- Answer choice 4-->
        <item>While</item> <!-- Answer -->

        <item>Which loop iterates over a sequence</item> <!-- Next question -->
        <item>Foreach</item>
        <item>For</item>
        <item>While</item>
        <item>When</item>
        <item >For</item>

        <item>What will be the third item printed: for char in "loop"</item> <!-- Next question -->
        <item>P</item>
        <item>L</item>
        <item>O</item>
        <item>char</item>
        <item >O</item>

        <item>How many times will this loop iterate? for x in range(7)</item> <!-- Next question -->
        <item>5</item>
        <item>9</item>
        <item>8</item>
        <item>7</item>
        <item >7</item>

    </string-array>
</resources>