<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="module_name">Module 1</string>

    <string name="lesson_name">Lesson 1</string>

    <string name="lesson_title">Variable Declaration</string>

    <string name="variables_intro">Variables are the basics of coding. Programs consist of
        instructions that tell the computer what to do. Variables are essential to this. They
        keep track of information. A variable is a value that is able to change depending on
        conditions or other information passed to the program. They can hold different data types
        such as an integer or a string. For example, you could create a variable named
        'example_string' and assign it a string: "Hello World!". Now if we tell the computer
        to print out the contents of 'example_string'. The computer would then print on the screen
        "Hello World!" In this lesson we will go over data types that can be stored in variables
        and how to declare them.</string>

    <string name="variable_declaration">Python has no command for declaring a variable. You simply
        type the desired name of the variable and assign it a value. </string>

    <string name="value_types">There are several types of variables. The most basic value types
        are Strings, Chars, Ints, Floats, and Booleans. Strings and Chars are character types. You
        use these data types to store text or single characters. Ints, or Integers, and Floats
        are number data types. Ints store whole numbers, cutting off decimal points (without
        rounding. It just truncates whatever is after the decimal point). For example if
        a variable named 'number' stored an Int data type but the value stored was 8.3, when asked
        to print 'number', the computer would print out just the number 8. Floats store the whole
        number including decimal points. So if our variable 'number' was a Float data type instead
        of an Int, when told to print 'number' the computer would print 8.3.</string>

    <string name="casting">What happens if you have a variable that stores an Int data type but you
        want to convert it to a Float data type so you can hold onto the decimal points? Changing
        data types is called CASTING. Lets look again at our previous example, an Int data type
        variable named 'number storing the value 8.3. We can CAST (or change) our variable type of
        Int to a Float by writing: float(number).</string>

    <string name="input">Now lets look at a common use of variables. Getting and storing input from
        a user. Say you want to write a program that will get someone\'s name and then two numbers
        that they want to get the sum of. You would need to get input from the user and store it in
        a variable. Your code would look something like this:

        name = input(println("What is your name? ))
        number1 = input(println("What is your first number? "))
        number2 = input(println("What is your second number?))

        Our variables are: 'name', 'number1', and 'number2'. We use input() to tell the program we
        want to get input from the user. println() tells the computer to print something to the
        screen.
    </string>

    <string name="example1">x = int(1)   # x will be 1
        y = int(2.8) # y will be 2
        z = int("3") # z will be 3</string>

    <string name="example2">x = float(1)     # x will be 1.0
        y = float(2.8)   # y will be 2.8
        z = float("3")   # z will be 3.0
        w = float("4.2") # w will be 4.2</string>
    <string name="example3">x = str("s1") # x will be \'s1\'
        y = str(2)    # y will be \'2\'
        z = str(3.0)  # z will be \'3.0\'</string>



    </resources>

